<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dawn Delatte</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>dawndelatte.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="dawndelatte.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 16:20:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 16:20:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Things</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;one&quot;&gt;One.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was demo-day for the Front End Engineering and Ruby on Rails classes at The Iron Yard. It has been a weird week leading up to it. Everyone has been hustling to get projects finished and teachers were busy takin’ care of business, but it all came together today and it was great. I cannot believe 12 weeks has gone by already for them. We were all babies in the beginning of the year and I am so impressed at what they can do now. So. damn. impressed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing those two classes working together and getting their apps working AND looking beautiful was amazing. Being there while they shared all of their anxieties about graduation and demo day was a little terrifying but I’ve gained some perspective and I’m looking forward to that experience myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got some really great advice from &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonweaver.name/blog/talking-to-industry-students&quot;&gt;Jason Weaver&lt;/a&gt; on work-life balance, always challenging yourself, and never selling yourself short. I’m thankful to be amongst such great developers and designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s my turn… We get our final project assignment this coming week. I’ll have more to say about that later I’m sure, for now, one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two&quot;&gt;Two.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s project—GoodReads web app redesign. Holy Moly this has been a tedious project. After a lot of research and feedback from other users, I opened up Photoshop to create my Style Tiles/Element Collages/Comps and haven’t closed it since. Three days of &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ustwo.com/PPP/PP3.pdf&quot;&gt;Pixel Perfect Precision&lt;/a&gt; and I’m still going. It’s been a pain staking process, but surprising enjoyable (and enlightening). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Oh the glory of being able to listen to music and podcasts while working again. I was never able to do that while coding. Next up—getting all my stuff portfolio-ready over the weekend, so stay tuned! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s crunch time y’all. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/twothings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/twothings/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>graduation,</category>
        
        <category>pixel,</category>
        
        <category>perfection,</category>
        
        <category>photoshop,</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Morphological Matrix</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;wowza&quot;&gt;Wowza!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been 3.5 weeks since I’ve written a blog post. In Iron Yard time that likes 2 light years? All the things have happened/been learned. Let me list a few before jumping into what I like to call the morphological mind maze of logo design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a weekend hackathon where one designer teamed up with a front end student and a back end student. That was an huge rush of emotions and energy and I made it out alive with an amazing project, new friends and role models, and a big ole medal for “best overall app” in all the land AKA The Iron Yard. You can check out my teams app &lt;a href=&quot;https://women-power.herokuapp.com/#/dashboard&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take some time in a later post to reflect on that eperience as well as some of my ideas for expanding on the design when I have a little more time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then dove right into coding our restaurant redesign projects that we have been reseraching and prototyping for the past few weeks. It was a challenge to get back into coding after spending time focusing on design theory, but it’s great to see things come full circle. Practice makes perfect! You can check out the progress of that project &lt;a href=&quot;http://dawndelatte.github.io/tiy_assignments/day_30/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are tackling logo design for our restaurants. I’ve been spending a lot of time in my sketchbook this week, which is a lovely and nostalgic feeling. While doing some  research for another project, I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juxtapoz.com/design/design-process-analog-vs-digital&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on digital vs analog design processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now – Would you like to take the red pill or the blue pill? 
Just kidding, you don’t have a choice. Welcome to the morphological matrix…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/morph_chart.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expanded on the word list I created a few weeks ago when creating style tiles and researching the theme of the website. From there, I used a “morphological matrix” to connect those words and phrases to icons or images that were associated. This was the basis for the 50 sketches that followed. I took two ideas/images and meshed them together by either random selection or to carry out an idea or theme I wanted to iterate a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/abgb_logos1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first round was awesome. And also hilarious. How does one draw a beer barrel and pizza together to form a simple logo? Or a picnic blanket and keg? I tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we critiqued and narrowed it down to a few logos to explore even further. Now we’re starting to get somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/abgb_logos2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/abgb_logos3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic bonus about this process was the fact that I was able to listen to music while working. I haven’t been able to do that since a lot of my work has been reading and coding. Music is good for the soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so excited to start using Illustrator and see what these sketches can really do. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 08:03:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/morphological/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/morphological/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>typography,</category>
        
        <category>exploring,</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Typography 201</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;typography-201&quot;&gt;Typography 201&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend we dove into using &lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com&quot;&gt;typecast&lt;/a&gt; to make some type specimens for an upcomming restuarant redesign project. I know I’m supposed to like it, but I’ve been so incredibly frustrated with it. I wanted so badly to layout some divs for my text so that I could get a good idea of how it will actaully look on the page. But that proved to be nearly impossible for me. I decided to leave positioning behind and refocus on the type and colors (which is what I was supposed to be doing anyway). Of course, once I was done with all 10 projects, typecast decided to delete one of them mid-save and I had to start over on it. But I prevailed! I hope. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to redesign &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theabgb.com&quot;&gt;Austin Beer Garden Brewery&lt;/a&gt; website. I started by making a list of words, phrases, and memories from my experiences there, as well as asking a couple of other people I know who frequent ABGB. I even worked up the nerve to email ABGB for some input! (Still waiting to hear back..) From there, I chose some key words and concepts and decided on some typeface and colors I thought would represent them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/type201.JPG&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/type201-2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the content from ABGB’s beer + food page and made a basic layout with h1-h3, p, a, and a few menu items to see how the font’s would look and feel next to each other. Once I got my typefaces down, I added a photo or two that represented a bit of the color theme I had decided on. I chose a few different elements to use the background colors on, as I don’t know exactly how they’ll fit into the layout quiet yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are rough drafts and although I’m a little anxious about sharing, I know it’s important — and also required! Some of the type and color themes are repeating throughout the 10 specimens but in no particular order. I tried to label each one with an indicator of what the inspiration basis was (food, community, or beer for instance). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/e19e5d063ae4aa66bbf80d77428d4baa0ad98bead&quot;&gt;abgb one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/ae77c49d3a23357fb0a7e08e7edb006b14edb0d9fZVRTCzg&quot;&gt;abgb two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/66ef17f582e5c51d2cbdfd6c8b1414fb0626f100w6m-qDJKX&quot;&gt;abgb three&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/e36ac2700a7616de50a1ceb5853e6c2e6d1bce54&quot;&gt;abgb four&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/f5cf26e7e5425268aec54a1afd4bde6fb22ac94eG&quot;&gt;abgb five&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/350ebfd637dddbfcb3102e2c7df8995ac3925731yqrw2R&quot;&gt;abgb six&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/76ad8d80ce6b36ccc84fec7eb4b1571836ccbe0ahFV2&quot;&gt;abgb seven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/cdcefcc6804801fa475e1f9e881de452731ff81fW8&quot;&gt;abgb eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/4a9d7e1189855a8a1c3c8b65d879beeaf616f384b&quot;&gt;abgb nine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typecast.com/3XPBgVFYVz/share/6c6de0b1cb65af0121b21501ab7c1bfe71a5caf1wk9X3jv-C2&quot;&gt;abgb ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been wonderful but also uneasy to transition into design. It seems so subjective, it’s hard to know if I’m “doing it right”. It’s probably time to let that go.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/typography201/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/typography201/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>typography,</category>
        
        <category>exploring,</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Typography 101</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;negative-space&quot;&gt;Negative Space.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve missed hearing those words. So much can be said about negative space, in art, in music, in typography.
“Positive” and “negative” space are equally important when creating or choosing a typeface. I could eat this stuff up all day. Good thing Sam is a little obsessed with it and doesn’t shy away from talking typography and design theory in general. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given an assignment to read through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designishistory.com/&quot;&gt;Design in History&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;bookmarked!&lt;/em&gt;) and come up with simple CodePens exploring google fonts and talking about things that inspired us about this site and these facilitators of great design. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;dPmgYb&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/dPmgYb/&quot;&gt;Exploring Typography&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;jEzedv&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/jEzedv/&quot;&gt;Exploring Typography&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;WbzaQE&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/WbzaQE/&quot;&gt;Exploring Typography&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;azYRwr&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/azYRwr/&quot;&gt;Exploring Typography &lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;wBmYOm&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/wBmYOm/&quot;&gt;Exploring Typography&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grumpy wizards make toxic brew for the evil Queen and Jack.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/typography101/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/typography101/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>typography,</category>
        
        <category>exploring,</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You are Here</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-four&quot;&gt;Week. Four.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m having &lt;strong&gt;all the feelings&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve been coding and coding, and sketching, and reading, and refactoring, and repositioning, and rethinking, and re… everything. Truthfully, when we are assigned a coding project, my initial reaction is &lt;em&gt;overwhelmed&lt;/em&gt; and a little &lt;em&gt;confused&lt;/em&gt;. And then things slooowwwwly start to happen on the page, and confidence is regained, and eventually the assignment is complete. It’s a total rollercoaster, but I love it. It’s really important for me to refocus and stay positive.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We responsified (not a word) Surf &amp;amp; Paddle.. Again, &lt;strong&gt;all the feelings&lt;/strong&gt;. “Retrofitting” a site I had done weeks earlier on a PIXEL PERFECT map… I mean?! There was a lot of absolute positions, amoung a multitude of other css I had to scrap. But that’s ok. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are talking design now. I feel like Sam &lt;em&gt;retrofit&lt;/em&gt; me back into art school. From critiques to design philosophy, I’m starting to feel like all this coding, all this cramming, and all this left brain action is taking form. They have meaning and purpose when I shift into a design perspective/mindset. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to make sure I get this stuff. I want to keep practicing the code and find ways to wrap my mind around positioning content, because that’s been the hardest part for me. This is why I love CodePen. It’s like a sketchbook for code. It’s amazing! All of my pens are simple and even ugly, but they help. Here’s one I did today while working on using my &lt;a href=&quot;dawndelatte.github.io/grids/&quot;&gt;grid formula&lt;/a&gt; with media queries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;GgxExX&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/GgxExX/&quot;&gt;RWD + Grids&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Edit in CodePen to see the responsiveness at work-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not as complicated as I was making it out to be in my mind. Math does that to me.. I just waited to introduce the grid formula until the largest media query, and thouhgt about my small and medium queries in percentages and bigger columns. Not everything has to fit into an elaborate grid to maintain consistancy, it’s just a guide that helps when simple percentages (like dividing the site into 2s or 3s) can’t! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as a sort of sign-off I’ll leave you with this…. “If you like it then you should have put a grid on it” - BeyonCSS&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/you_are_here/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/you_are_here/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>layouts,</category>
        
        <category>responsive,</category>
        
        <category>design,</category>
        
        <category>rwd,</category>
        
        <category>grids,</category>
        
        <category>journey,</category>
        
        <category>brain,</category>
        
        <category>function</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic RWD Codepens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In class today, we were assigned a few basic responsive CodePens to make playing around with different meida queries and seeing how we can make content reflow. If you want to see them at work, you’ll have to “edit on CodePen”. Check em out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a basic one-breakpoint layout, where global is 200px width and 50% after breakpoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;yyvqVy&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/yyvqVy/&quot;&gt;RWD one&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a two-breakpoint layout with a third div, making them 33% at the second breakpoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;WbMKpq&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/WbMKpq/&quot;&gt;RWD two&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this one is three breakpoints, with all three divs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;WbMKEV&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/WbMKEV/&quot;&gt;RWD three&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a “wrapper” that scales with the page and has a max-width of 1000px:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;yyvqqO&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/yyvqqO/&quot;&gt;RWD wrapper&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like plain ole’ primary color boxes I know.. but for me learning RWD is a whole new great big world. I’m looking foward to diving in and becoming a responsible-responsive-designer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/rwd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/rwd/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>layouts,</category>
        
        <category>responsive,</category>
        
        <category>design,</category>
        
        <category>rwd</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grids</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;dawn--1&quot;&gt;Dawn : 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grids--0&quot;&gt;Grids : 0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are learning about grids y’all. It seems like an simple enough concept. Make a grid with columns and gutters, do a little math, and voilà! We had a great lecture, devised a genius formula, and I was feeling pretty good about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid_embed&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-height=&quot;214&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;OPzWvL&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/OPzWvL/&quot;&gt;12 column grid with col-num formula&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then we were given ten sites to look at, decide their grid layouts, and draw them in our moleskines (thanks TIY!) I eased into the first few sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nest.com/&quot;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/&quot;&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt; with fairly straight forward layouts, then Sam hit us with things like her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005GK3IVW/ref=ox_sc_act_title_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&quot;&gt;Roomba product page on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; … What is that?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/grid7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/grid2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/journal_assets/grid3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started “coloring outside the lines” if you will. I wouldn’t say I’m a perfectionist by any stretch of the imagination but this was &lt;strong&gt;hard&lt;/strong&gt;. What should have taken about 2 hours, took me 6 and it was the first time I was rushing to “complete” an assignment minutes before class started. Commiting to &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; lines with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; pen made html look like strawberry cupcakes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mmmm cupcakes. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/grids/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/grids/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>grids,</category>
        
        <category>layouts,</category>
        
        <category>cupcakes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Middle Ground</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-middle-ground&quot;&gt;On &lt;em&gt;Middle&lt;/em&gt; Ground&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to feel like I get it.. sort of.. I think. There are no big lows, thank goodness, and no big highs, besides still being here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned a video to watch in our weekend homework that really put some things into perspective. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1i8ylq4j_EY&quot;&gt;It’s Dangerous to go Alone&lt;/a&gt; talks about &lt;em&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/em&gt; and ways to help yourself or your coworkers overcome some of the hurdles people with insecurities about their skills face (eg. &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind is in a continual state of &lt;strong&gt;blown&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m starting to feel like myself, except that there’s this weird state you get in when you code for too long without a break called HYSTERIA. That’s where the singing happens, and puns happen (get it – git it?), and it’s also where your mind shuts down and everything you know to be true is not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when you need a break, sun shine and/or food. It’s amazing the amount of time you can spend on one itty bitty problem only to take a quick shower and discover mid-rinse that you put the right information in THE WRONG PLACE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned, Week Two, lesson learned. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/middle_ground/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/middle_ground/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>imposter-syndrome,</category>
        
        <category>breaks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Floating</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;floating-left-in-a-sea-of-unfamiliarity&quot;&gt;Floating &lt;em&gt;(Left)&lt;/em&gt; in a Sea of Unfamiliarity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day is finally here! I have started my journey at The Iron Yard. After months of wavering between feelings of excitment and slight terror, I jumped in … sort of blindly. I had already attended a week of the Front End Engineering class, so I felt like I had a good “practice round” in. But nothing really prepared me for the sheer amount of information and exercise my brain was getting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my classmates and fellow iron yarders were so willing to share their experiences and insights. I found myself learning a lot more than &lt;strong&gt;HTML&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CSS&lt;/strong&gt;. I was (and still am) trying to learn about myself and how I work and what kind of attitudes hold me back or help me to move forward.  I am learning to trust. To trust my instructors, my peers, and myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week was overwhelming, but not in the way that I expected. I was overwhelmed with feelings of self-doubt and anxiety, and that was matched by encouragment from Sam and the other Iron Yard team leaders. This is a community of people who were in the same &lt;em&gt;sea&lt;/em&gt;, on their own boats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never considered myself a great student in college. So I felt like this was my second chance. This was a challenge though when I began to feel inadequite because the ever illusive “click” was not happening. I know, I know, nothing’s going to click in the first week, but quieting those thoughts are a lot harder for me. The more I worked, and the further we got in class, the more I realized that the clicking was there, but it came in what I like to call a “gentle whisper”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week One left me &lt;strike&gt;feeling&lt;/strike&gt; knowing that I was, in fact, in the right place and had made the right decision to leave it all behind, and join The Iron Yard in song and pun into a &lt;em&gt;whole new world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/floating_left/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/floating_left/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
