<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dawn Delatte</title>
    <description>This is the portfolio and journal site for an Austin-based designer, Dawn Delatte.
</description>
    <link>dawndelatte.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="dawndelatte.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 19:09:58 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 19:09:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grids</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;dawn--1&quot;&gt;Dawn : 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grids--0&quot;&gt;Grids : 0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are learning about grids y’all. It seems like an simple enough concept. Make a grid with columns and gutters, do a little math, and voilà! We had a great lecture, devised a genius formula, and I was feeling pretty good about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid_embed&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-height=&quot;214&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12242&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;OPzWvL&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;dawndelatte&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte/pen/OPzWvL/&quot;&gt;12 column grid with col-num formula&lt;/a&gt; by Dawn Delatte (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dawndelatte&quot;&gt;@dawndelatte&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then we were given ten sites to look at, decide their grid layouts, and draw them in our moleskines (thanks TIY!) I eased into the first few sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nest.com/&quot;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/&quot;&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt; with fairly straight forward layouts, then Sam hit us with things like her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005GK3IVW/ref=ox_sc_act_title_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&quot;&gt;Roomba product page on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; … What is that?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;grid_imgs&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grids_row1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grid7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grids_row2&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grid2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;!--
	--&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grid3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started “coloring outside the lines” if you will. I wouldn’t say I’m a perfectionist by any stretch of the imagination but this was &lt;strong&gt;hard&lt;/strong&gt;. What should have taken about 2 hours, took me 6 and it was the first time I was rushing to “complete” an assignment minutes before class started. Commiting to &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; lines with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; pen made html look like strawberry cupcakes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mmmm cupcakes. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/grids/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/grids/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>grids,</category>
        
        <category>layouts,</category>
        
        <category>cupcakes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Middle Ground</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-middle-ground&quot;&gt;On &lt;em&gt;Middle&lt;/em&gt; Ground&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to feel like I get it.. sort of.. I think. There are no big lows, thank goodness, and no big highs, besides still being here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned a video to watch in our weekend homework that really put some things into perspective. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1i8ylq4j_EY&quot;&gt;It’s Dangerous to go Alone&lt;/a&gt; talks about &lt;em&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/em&gt; and ways to help yourself or your coworkers overcome some of the hurdles people with insecurities about their skills face (eg. &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind is in a continual state of &lt;strong&gt;blown&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m starting to feel like myself, except that there’s this weird state you get in when you code for too long without a break called HYSTERIA. That’s where the singing happens, and puns happen (get it – git it?), and it’s also where your mind shuts down and everything you know to be true is not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when you need a break, sun shine and/or food. It’s amazing the amount of time you can spend on one itty bitty problem only to take a quick shower and discover mid-rinse that you put the right information in THE WRONG PLACE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned, Week Two, lesson learned. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/middle_ground/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/middle_ground/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy,</category>
        
        <category>imposter-syndrome,</category>
        
        <category>breaks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Floating</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;floating-left-in-a-sea-of-unfamiliarity&quot;&gt;Floating &lt;em&gt;(Left)&lt;/em&gt; in a Sea of Unfamiliarity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day is finally here! I have started my journey at The Iron Yard. After months of wavering between feelings of excitment and slight terror, I jumped in … sort of blindly. I had already attended a week of the Front End Engineering class, so I felt like I had a good “practice round” in. But nothing really prepared me for the sheer amount of information and exercise my brain was getting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my classmates and fellow iron yarders were so willing to share their experiences and insights. I found myself learning a lot more than &lt;strong&gt;HTML&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CSS&lt;/strong&gt;. I was (and still am) trying to learn about myself and how I work and what kind of attitudes hold me back or help me to move forward.  I am learning to trust. To trust my instructors, my peers, and myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week was overwhelming, but not in the way that I expected. I was overwhelmed with feelings of self-doubt and anxiety, and that was matched by encouragment from Sam and the other Iron Yard team leaders. This is a community of people who were in the same &lt;em&gt;sea&lt;/em&gt;, on their own boats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never considered myself a great student in college. So I felt like this was my second chance. This was a challenge though when I began to feel inadequite because the ever illusive “click” was not happening. I know, I know, nothing’s going to click in the first week, but quieting those thoughts are a lot harder for me. The more I worked, and the further we got in class, the more I realized that the clicking was there, but it came in what I like to call a “gentle whisper”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week One left me &lt;strike&gt;feeling&lt;/strike&gt; knowing that I was, in fact, in the right place and had made the right decision to leave it all behind, and join The Iron Yard in song and pun into a &lt;em&gt;whole new world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 07:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>dawndelatte.github.io/floating_left/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">dawndelatte.github.io/floating_left/</guid>
        
        <category>tiy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
